<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-12-17T16:35:20-05:00</updated><id>/</id><title type="html">Optic</title><subtitle>Automate Work, Share Knowledge, Enforce Convention</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Optic Update #1</title><link href="/blog/optic-update-1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Optic Update #1" /><published>2017-12-16T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-12-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/blog/optic-update-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/optic-update-1/">&lt;p&gt;Today we launched the first version of our website here at opticdev.com. Thanks for your visit! We’re not quite done yet; our docs, video gallery and team pages are forthcoming. For now we really just wanted to get something up for all of you as we create &amp;amp; iterate the content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest question you’re probably left with after perusing our site is our timeline. Right now we’re planning to release most of our open source research in January of 2018 through a series of blog posts, public repos, and documentation. While that’s going on, the first couple users will get private access to the Optic Agent to start testing it in the real world. Our intent is to release the Agent publicly within a month or two of that testing (bearing any unforeseen issues). We’ll be releasing periodic updates on this blog throughout that entire process in case you choose to follow us closely during that time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our small team has been pretty heads down building our MVP over the last few months. It’s been a lot of R&amp;amp;D and our rationale for releasing our research before the product is that we really want to get the biases of the R&amp;amp;D phase out of our system. The best way we can think to do that is to put it all down on paper and move along. Yes, we’re excited about what we’ve built and the leanings it incorporates from our past companies and experiences, but we’re more anxious to work closely with &lt;strong&gt;real&lt;/strong&gt; users to solve their &lt;strong&gt;real&lt;/strong&gt; problems. That’s the sort of team we are. If you work with us in the early days we’ll be there for you, side-by-side, solving real issues that face you and your teams. If you pull up a chair for us in your office, one of us will come sit in it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy [insert holiday here]! We look forward to getting to know all of you soon.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">Launch plans, research releases, and other musings</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/images/blog/startingblock.jpg" /></entry></feed>
